## **Craig Inscore**

IT Senior Program Manager / IT Manager

cinscore@silverliningranch.net

## Summary

I have more than 25 years working in IT as a Project Manager, IT Consultant, Director of a large IT organization, software developer and business analyst. I have extensive experience managing multiple projects from inception, planning and design through development and implementation. My major accomplishments include migrating corporate legacy systems to new technologies, managing new development projects and designing software application systems. My experience includes software application development and project management experience in financial, mortgage, healthcare, telecomm, real estate and other industries. I have worked closely with KPMG consultants to successfully implement new financial systems and migrate legacy systems to new technologies. My current contract is working with the State of TN on their Medicaid Modernization Project (MMP). In conjunction with KMPG and numerous other contracting firms my responsibilities are to review the vendor contracts, and to formulate a transition plan for the SPMO Contractor. The main objective is to create a Strategic PMO transition plan. This is a fast track program and there are many deliverables as defined in the contracts for the TAS Contractor, the SPMO Contractor and the State.

## Experience

#### IT Consulant / Senior Project Manager

May 2000 - Present

- More than 20 years working in IT as a project manager, software developer, business analyst, IT Consultant and Director of a large IT organization.
- Extensive experience managing multiple projects from inception and design through development and implementation. My major accomplishments include migrating corporate legacy systems to new technologies, managing new development projects and designing software application systems. My experience includes software application development and project management experience in financial, mortgage, healthcare, telecomm, real estate and other industries.
- Used MS Project Server and SharePoint extensively for managing projects, tracking issues and managing risks. I also used SharePoint for tracking servers, SQL databases, status reporting, etc.
- Worked closely with KPMG consultants to successfully implement new financial systems and migrate legacy systems to new technologies.

#### **Program Manager - MMIS Modernization**

May 2016 - May 2017 (1 year 1 month)

The State of Pennsylvania initiated their Medicaid Management Information System (MMIS) Modernization Program to migrate their current legacy system to the Center for Medicaid and Medicare Services) (CMS) Medicaid Information Technical Architecture. (MITA) Modularity requirements for CMS Certification. The replacement system is to be modular in design and requires interoperability between all modules, interfaces and services.

The modularity requirements of the CMS Standards and conditions require that multiple RFPs be created and released for bid. This requires the definition of business requirements, SLAs, RFPs and a coordination of State, Contractors, and CMS as well as Federal regulations.

Responsibilities included facilitating meetings, providing comprehensive projects status, and meeting with Executive Management.

I am responsible for building the State team for this effort and will create numerous Requests for Proposals for the various services and software required to successfully complete this project. The Program has a combined budget of more than \$150 Million dollars. To date we have brought on team members and are in the process of completing several of the required RFPs.

The objective of this Program and projects is to have a fully compliant and certified MITA 3.0 system that will meet both the State, Federal, and CMS requirements as well as business partners and clients.

#### Sr. Project Manager

October 2015 - May 2016 (8 months)

State of Tennessee HCFA Medicaid Modernization Project - IT Sr. Project Manager October, 2015 – Current, 2015 (contract)

I have been assigned to assist the TAS (Technical Advisory Services) Contractor (KPMG) with the Startup and onboarding process for the State's major program to modernize and update their State Medicaid systems (MMIS and MMP). My role is to review, analyze and provide a comprehensive assessment of the contracts awarded to numerous State of TN contractors for the Program. I am currently working on the onboarding process between the Technical Advisory Services Contractor (TAS) and the Strategic Project Management Office (SPMO) Contractor. This effort has a fast track approach and requires in depth strategies for the various contracting vendors to work in cooperation to fulfill the State's requirements. The creation of a formal RFQ and RFP for the Systems Integrator (SI) is in process and the expected review by the State and the Center for Medicaid Services (CMS) is pending.

#### **Senior Project Manager**

January 2015 - August 2015 (8 months)

•HMSA (Hawaii Medical Systems Association – BlueCross BlueShield of Hawaii) - IT Project Manager January, 2015 – July, 2015 (contract)

At HMSA I was assigned to 4 of HMSA's top 5 projects since joining HMSA in January of 2015. These projects all required strong utilization of MS Office, MS Project Professional and MS Project Server as well as SharePoint and PowerPoint. I was responsible for resource allocation, estimating and budgeting on all of the projects that I was responsible for.

As Project Manager I have managed the MFSD (Mainframe Shutdown) project and the MSRP (Membership Replacement Project). This effort was to integrate the QNXT (TMS) software system to an EAM integration project. I lead the project team in research and scheduled vendor demonstrations with the vendor and the business owners. I worked with Cognizant, an IT consulting firm to determine requirements and schedule meetings and demos with the business owners group.

I was assigned to the Annual Open Enrollment Project as the primary project manager. This project was to manage the activities associated with the Annual Open Enrollment activities and tasks. This project had high visibility and priority due to the past years' issues and problems that required correction and remediation.

In May, 2015 I was also assigned to HMSA's high priority security effort to upgrade, remediate and decommission their Windows Server 2003 servers. This effort required the identity of owners, applications, and DBs as well as planning and, upgrade strategies of 161 Windows 2003 Servers. The venerability and exposure to these servers was due to the impending end of life support for Windows Server 2003, date July 14, 2015.

### IT Consultant - Project Management at Centene Corporation

May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months)

Led a major project required to successfully implement a new healthcare eligibility system using new technologies for this Fortune 150 firm. This effort had been in progress for over a year and had a contract deliverable date of August 1, 2013. This effort was required to fulfill a contract with a large Medicaid customer followed by an implementation of the marketplace software application for numerous state contracts for Medicaid. The project required mapping of HIPAA 834 flat files from the customer to the XML file format required for the input source to the UMV (Unified Member View) product. Additional file transfers were required for the legacy (AMISYS) system. The project was successfully implemented on time.

A significant factor in the success of this implementation was the improvement of communications between the key stakeholders. A perceived lack of communication between the business and technical areas was remedied which resulted in better communication of business requirements, issues and successfully meeting critical timelines.

#### IT Consultant at BlueCross BlueShield of SC

#### June 2007 - May 2013 (6 years)

Significant accomplishments: Provided direction in the redesign numerous corporate applications including the corporate website, Intranet and help desk knowledge base applications. Worked on multiple efforts for the enhancement of the corporate document repository and redesigning the front end document search user interface. Provided direction in the migration of the corporate content management system to new technologies.

I managed projects for BCBSSC web sites for their internet Website migration, SouthCarolinaBlues.com and the company's intranet site. I also managed the project for the company's internal knowledge base application system for the Technical Support Team.

Responsible for numerous projects from inception through implementation using the companies structured methodologies. Responsible for estimating efforts, phase progression and collaboration between the project management, development and testing teams.

Responsible for key areas of Medicaid and TRICARE projects and compliance with HIPAA regulations and system level agreements (SLAs). Data mapping was required for the HIPAA flat files and XML processes. Developed numerous whitepapers to research solutions for various critical applications and provided input for large RFPs within time constraints.

Was e member of the BCBSSC Executive IT Steering Committee for more than 4 years.

#### IT Consultant / Project Manager at Monsanto

December 2006 - June 2007 (7 months)

As the lead Project/System Design Analyst for this large corporation I was responsible for the automation and implementation of software applications for new companies that the client had acquired. This position required working with the development team and the client to define business and system requirements to meet the various business needs of each client company. I helped identify business critical areas in management reporting and system functionality and made recommendations that were successfully implemented. These enhancements provided the companies with valuable new management tools that significantly improved their ability to manage inventory and to increase sales.

#### CEO, President

July 2000 - December 2006 (6 years 6 months)

RES Solutions provides a comprehensive, state of the art software solution for the real estate and mortgage banking industries covering Relocation, Property Management, Leasing Services and Resort Rentals applications.

Additional services:

• Seeing a need for a comprehensive software solution in the Real Estate industry I formed RES Solutions. I brought together a development team to design, develop and implement a solution based on Oracle DB for

scalability. I managed the development team working with business leaders in the Real Estate industry to define the business requirements. The result was a comprehensive Real Estate software solution.

- Provided consulting services for Project Management, Business and Systems Analysis, Application Integration and Project Planning. Other services include the integration of third party software and corporate acquisitions consulting services.
- Designed and developed Oracle 9i and 8i Databases based on application requirements.

#### IT Director at Long and Foster, REALTORS

July 1993 - May 2003 (9 years 11 months)

Responsible for the daily management of Long & Foster's Real Estate corporate production IT applications (Commissions, AP, GL, HR & Payroll, Fixed Assets, Property Management, Leasing Services, Relocation and Marketing). Directed the corporate IT systems through Y2K and migrated the applications to new technologies. I worked closely with KPMG in the integration and implementation of the new Great Plains Dynamics financial systems.

- Provided system and project management of all production business applications for this \$30 billion/year Real Estate Company based in Fairfax, VA.
- Managed a project to develop a Direct Mail Marketing system for over 10,000 sales agents. This direct mail center system resulted in a significant amount of business to the agents by providing a mass mail/marketing tool to attract prospective clients. The inclusion of a USPS CASS certification software resulted in significant postage savings to the company, estimated at more than \$30,000 per month.
- Managed projects to develop financial applications interfaces to a new financial Accounting system, Great Plains Dynamics, AP, GL and Payroll/HR. These interfaces were developed to integrate the companies' business systems to the Great Plains Dynamics financial system. I led the project working with a team of developers and KPMG consultants to map and develop the interfaces to a new technology environment.
- Managed numerous other projects in support of Long & Foster's business requirements. These were business critical projects to automate business processes or replace existing, aging software applications.

#### **Director of IT at Long & Foster Companies**

July 1993 - May 2002 (8 years 11 months)

Responsible for the daily management of Long & Foster's Real Estate corporate IT applications (Commissions, AP, GL, HR & Payroll, Fixed Assets, Property Management, Leasing Services, Relocation and Marketing). Directed the corporate IT systems through Y2K and migrated the applications to new technologies. I was instrumental in launching e-commerce for Resort Rentals, Leasing Services and Relocation.

• Provided system and project management of all production business systems for this \$30 billion/year Real Estate Company based in Fairfax, VA.

- Provided project management related to Long & Foster's e-commerce internet sites including Leasing Services, Relocation and Resort Rentals. These efforts were done using an Oracle platform.
- Managed projects to develop a Direct Mail Marketing system for over 9,000 agents. This direct mail center resulted in a significant amount of business to the agents by providing a mass mail/marketing tool to attract prospective clients.
- Developed financial applications interfaces to a new financial Accounting system, Great Plains, AP, GL and Payroll/HR. These interfaces were developed to integrate the companies' business systems to the Great Plains financial system. I led the project working with a team of developers to map and develop the interfaces to a new technology environment.

.

#### IT Conultant / Project Manager at Ingram Barge Company

October 1992 - July 1993 (10 months)

• Provided project management, business analysis and software development for the company's barge traffic tracking systems. The application used satellite links from the river vessels to computer operations in Nashville for the purpose of tracking vessel locations and significant events, crew, fuel and barge loads.

## Education

#### **Rockwell University**

Bachelor's degree, IT Management / e-commerce, 2003 - 2004

Activities and Societies: IT Management, e-commerce, Oracle DBA, Java, JDBC, JSP, XML

University of Missouri-Columbia, College of Business

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Business, Pshychology, Philosophy, 1978 - 1982

# **Craig Inscore**

IT Senior Program Manager / IT Manager

cinscore@silverliningranch.net



Contact Craig on LinkedIn